Gather round, come take a look...
It's time for Theatre of Darkness.
DECIDE
This is the story of a certain junior high school girl...
My mom can do everything.
She helps me with my homework,
and her cooking and sewing are perfect.
She's my pride and joy.
Minori,
I baked an apple pie for your snack.
Come eat!
Really?! Yay!
Hm,
actually Mom,
I want to go to Yami High School.
That high school that's so hard to get into?
Yeah.
I want to give it a shot.
I see.
Alright.
Let me think about it for a bit.
No matter what I consult her about,
my mom's face never darkens.
She always helps me make the right decisions for my future.
About yesterday's talk about high school...
do as you like, Minori.
Is it really okay?
I thought you'd be safer aiming for a school you're guaranteed to pass,
but I'll support you.
Thank you! I'll do my best!
My father wasn't around for as long as I can remember.
I never felt lonely,
but,
he must have been a terrible guy for abandoning my mother.
I promised myself I'd never let her be sad again.
Mom!
I passed!
Congratulations, Minori!
You're my proud daughter!
My mother raised me all by herself.
From now on, I wanted her to take it easy.
For just a second,
it felt like my mother's smile,
froze.
Mom, I'm home!
Is Mom on the phone with someone?
Could it be Dad?
That jerk?
Mom...?
...But then, I saw it.
From now on,
will I no longer be asking for your advice about that girl?
I never imagined a day like this would come...
My mom had been consulting him all this time.
That guy.
After that,
while my mom was out,
I secretly snuck into her room.
Damn it, it's locked!
I can't forgive this!
To think he was manipulating my beloved mother.
Give my mom back!
Give my mom back! GIVE MY MOM BACK!
Minori, I'm sorry I'm late!
I'll make dinner right away—
Minori...?
Why...?
The dresser was empty.
After that my mother,
couldn't manage the housework anymore,
and our home fell apart.
My mother
became unable to speak, except one thing...
Decide...
Eat the bread.
Go to the bathroom when you're done.
It's okay.
From now on, I'll decide.
I'll decide everything for you.
THE END
SCENE NOTE:
When the girl destroys what was inside the room (thinking her father was manipulating her mother through the phone/altar/relic),
her mother was actually relying on that entity/object to make every single decision in her life. Upon its destruction, the mother falls into a vegetative/catatonic state, repeating only the word "decide" (kimete).